SIMRAN AMIN

PROFILE

I am a 2021 graduate of Dental Surgery at the University of Liverpool where I graduated with honours and achieved distinctions in both oral diseases and oral health. In 2017, I graduated from the University of Cambridge where I studied Natural Sciences with a special interest in pathology and pharmacology. Alongside my clinical training I enjoy working digitally with 4 years of experience working remotely as an editor to provide digital examination resources for prospective medical school applicants alongside creating guidance documentation for onboarding new writers. With my interest in technology, writing and design, I am looking to pivot towards an alternative career in health or tech where I can grow these skills and contribute to the wider community in a non-clinical environment.

EDUCATION

2017-2021 University of Liverpool (4 years)

Bachelor of Dental Surgery with Honours (Graduate Entry Pathway)

Distinction in Oral Diseases Distinction in Oral Health

2014-2017 University of Cambridge (3 years)

Natural Sciences - Bachelor of Arts with Honours

Part II: High 2:1 (69%) - Pharmacology

Part 1B: High 2:1 (69%) - Pathology, Pharmacology, Developmental Biology Part 1A: High 2:1 (67%) - Physiology, Cellular Biology, Chemistry, Maths

2007–2014 The Tiffin Girls' School, Kingston upon Thames

A-levels: A2 Biology (A*) A2 Chemistry (A*) A2 Maths (A*), AS Art (A)

GCSEs: 11, 10 at grade A* including Maths, English Language, French, Spanish OCR Level 2 Certificate in Creative iMedia (Website design, Video editing)

DIGITAL SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Adobe Photoshop | Procreate | Microsoft Powerpoint, Excel and Word | Basic HTML/CSS | Figma

Portfolio Project (ongoing): http://simranamin.com/

2023 Coursera: Stanford University - Writing in the Sciences Course (with Honors)
Learned the principles of good scientific writing, practised editing samples of

scientific text and peer reviewed assignments from other participants.

freeCodeCamp: Responsive Web Design Certification

Learned basic HTML/CSS to create a variety of webpages including a survey form, tribute page, product landing page, technical documentation page and personal

portfolio

2016 Institute of Digital Marketing: Creative Data Academy

Selected to enroll in a 3 day programme where I learned about principles of data analysis and participated in marketing projects for companies such as Mercedes

Benz and Feel Unique

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

2021	MFDS Part 1	(Roval	College of	Surgeons of	of England)

2020 ABAOMS Essay Prize

	Liverpool winner for essay titled 'The Impact of Human Factors on Oral Surgery'
2019	Dental Alumni Prize
	Highest overall mark for 3 rd BDS Oral Science & Medicine Knowledge Examinations
2019	Mark Ball Memorial Prize
	Highest overall mark for 3 rd BDS Evidence Based Virtual Case Report Presentation
2018	Robert Grieve Memorial Prize
	Highest overall mark for 2 nd BDS Oral Science and Medicine Critical Reasoning Paper
2017	Churchill College Academic Prize
	For attaining high examination results in Part II pharmacology
	J J

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2022-ongoing Family Dental Practice: PLVE Dentist (10 months)

 Carry out both NHS and private treatments while working to complete my postgraduation training, in continuation from the previous role

2021-2022 Together Dental Wandsworth: Dental Foundation Trainee (4 months)

- Provided preventative and basic general dental care within a diverse high needs NHS practice
- Carried out local audits on hand hygiene, infection control, radiographic record keeping and staff documentation

2017-2021 Medify: UCAT Abstract Reasoning Editor (4 years)

- Remotely trained new members of the team and created written guides to support new question writers with question writing and admin interfaces
- Reviewed and edited submissions from question writers to regulate quality and ensure clarity of written explanations
- Created practice questions and mock examinations conforming to the UCAT specification
- Responsible for managing and resolving web content problems reported by Medify users over peak exam season

OTHER POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

2015-2017 University of Cambridge: President of Churchill College Art Society

- Organised and lead weekly drawing, painting and origami sessions
- Commissioned by Churchill College to illustrate a Fresher's week backdrop
- Managed the annual budget for art expenses

ARTICLES AND PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Amin, S. (2018). 'Are you considering Graduate Dentistry?', UniAdmissions
- 2. Amadeu de Oliveira, F., MacVinish, L. J., Amin, S., Herath, D., Jeggle, P., Mela, I., Pieri, M., Sharma, C., Jarvis, G. E., Levy, F. M., Santesso, M. R., Khan, Z. N., Leite, A. L., Oliveira, R. C., Buzalaf, M. A. R. and Edwardson, J. M. (2018) 'The effect of fluoride on the structure, function, and proteome of intestinal epithelia', *Environmental Toxicology*, 33(1), pp. 63-71. doi: 10.1002/TOX.22495.